A few days ago,
we posted a poll on Insurance Impact's YouTube channel
asking you
which two other
plans you'd like to compare the ICC Lombard Elevate plan with. The
two plans that received the most votes
are Care Health Insurance's
Supreme plan, and the other plan you'd
like to compare is AIG's
Buddy Care Premier plan. In today's video, we'll
compare all three plans. We'll explore the
eligibility criteria for these plans, the
differences you'll face
in coverage and benefits, and
which plan will
suit you best when you claim the policy. After discussing everything in detail,
I'll also share my verdict.
I'll explain the
strengths and weaknesses of these plans so
you can get a clear conclusion from the comparison. At the end of the video,
we'll compare the prices of all three policies,
which is the most important part.
You're getting coverage, but
We will also compare these three plans to find out how much they will cost. So,
if you are
interested in taking any of these three plans, or you already
have these policies and want to compare them,
you want to port them, or you are
buying a fresh insurance policy, then
today's comparison video will prove to be very beneficial for you.
You will get clarity through this video, so let's not delay
and quickly start the video.
First of all, let's understand the eligibility conditions of all these three plans. The
first
point we will discuss is the entry
age. If we talk about the ICICI Lombard
Elevate plan, the entry
age for adults is from 18 years to 125 years, that is, there is
no capping on the maximum entry age.
If we talk about dependent children,
they can be a part of the ICCI Lombard Elevate plan from 91 days to 30 years. Let's
talk about the Care Supreme plan,
here the entry age for adults is 18 years
and the maximum entry age is
It will remain for 99 years, which means you
can call it no capping. Dependent
children can become
part of the Care Health Supreme plan from 911 days to 24 years of age.
If we talk about the Tata EIG
Medicare Premier plan,
adults can buy this policy from 18 years to 65 years of age,
and dependent
children can live
with their parents under the Tata EIG Medicare
Premier policy from 91 days to 25 years of age.
Friends, if the policy is taken within this age band,
whether it is an adult or a dependent
child, but after that this age band is
crossed, can we renew this policy for
life, or will it
also be discontinued later, or is there any
age capping on renewal?
Talking about renewal, there is no capping in all three plans.
You
can renew it for life. Now comes the turn to
discuss the tenure. How long can you
take a policy for in all three plans simultaneously?  You
can choose 1 year, 2 years and 3 year policies together. If you choose 2 and 3
year plans along with long term plan,
then all three plans offer you some
discounts as well. How many types
of policies can you take? Both the options are
available in all the three plans i.e.
ICICI Lord Elevate Plan, Care Supreme
and Tata AIG Medicare Premier Plan.
You can take both individual and family floater plans.
Now
friends, a very important point comes that is the sum
insured i.e. how much coverage you will be
able to take in these three plans. So first of all let us
understand the sum insured of ICICI Lord Elevate plan. The minimum sum
insured is ₹ lakh and
you can take a maximum sum insurance of ₹ crore,
but there is also an option of unlimited sum insured in it, that is, in which there is
no limit on the sum insured. If we talk about
Care Supreme plan, then here the
sum insurance ranges from ₹ lakh to ₹ crore.  You can choose the shard
and in the Tata EIG Medicare
Premier plan, you
can choose the sum insured from ₹1 lakh to ₹3 crore, that
is, the maximum sum insured you will get is
in the ICICI Lord Elevate plan
and in the Tata EIG Medicare Premier plan. The
minimum sum insured in the Care Health Insurance plan is ₹1 lakh and the maximum
sum insured is also up to ₹1 crore. Are there
any variants in these three plans, that is, are there any
other sub-plans in it or will it
remain the standard variant only? If we talk about the
ICICI Lord Elevate plan, then here the
insurance company gives you two options,
two types of packages, one is the basic
pack in which you will be given all the add-ons separately,
whatever you choose will be
added to your plan. Apart from this, an essential
pack is also offered by the company, in
which it is compulsory to take the five add-ons. So, the
premium will be charged according to whichever package you choose,
whereas in the Care Supreme
plan, there is only one standard plan.
You don't have to make any separate decision or choice.
You
can add some advances to the standard plan itself. There are no separate variants
within the Tata Medicare Premier plan. What's
special is that there are
no special advances in this plan.
Whatever features you need, whatever coverage you want, are
part of the standard plan itself, which we will
understand in the coverage and benefits section later. Now friends, let's
understand the coverage and benefits of all these three plans one by one. The
first point we will discuss is the room rent
limit. When a policyholder
goes to the hospital for treatment, which
category of room will he get, that is, the expenses for which he can
claim. So,
under the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan,
which is a standard policy,
you can claim expenses up to a single private AC room. Whereas,
under the Care Supreme plan and the Tata
Medicare Premier plan, there is no
room rent capping. Now let's talk about
day treatment procedures, that is,
such small medical  Procedures which do
not require admission for a full 24 hours, that is, the patient is treated within a short time
and is discharged on the same day, so
day treatments
are also covered in all these three plans. Now let's talk about domicile
treatment and home care treatment. Both of these are
such treatments which can be taken at home.
Domicile treatment is
taken at home due to some compulsion, that is, the patient
is not in a condition to be taken to the hospital
or there are no beds available in the hospitals to
keep the patient, then
treatment can be taken at home as well. Domicile
treatment is covered in all the three plans
but there is a difference in home care
treatment. If we talk about home care treatment, then
home
care treatment is not covered in the Elevate plan.
Home care treatment
is covered in the Care Supreme plan and there is coverage of home treatment in the Tata AAG Medicare
Premier plan,
but for that, a
sum insured of Rs 75 lakh or more is necessary.
Now friends,
It is also important to understand the difference in the number of days of post-hospitalization expenses. The
number of days of coverage you get in the IIC Lombard Elevate plan is 90
days and 180 days, that is, 90 days of pre-
hospitalization and 180 days of post-
hospitalization expenses will be covered.
Whereas, under the Care Supreme plan, you can claim 60
days of pre-hospitalization and 180 days of post-
hospitalization expenses.
And under the Tata AIG Medicare Premier
plan, 60 days of pre-hospitalization
and 90 days of post-hospitalization expenses will be
covered. However, there is a difference here.
If your sum assured is Rs 75 lakh or more in the Tata AIG Medicare Premier plan, then the
limit of number of days of post-hospitalization increases from 90 days to
200 days, that is,
you will be able to cover expenses up to 200 days for post-
hospitalization expenses in Tata AIG
Medicare Premier.  Now let's talk about the
road ambulance plan, that is, if in an emergency
situation a road ambulance has to be used to
admit a patient or a shoulder,
then how much
amount of claim will be covered in these policies?
In the IIC Lord Elevate plan, the
road ambulance expenses are actual on the covered age.
Under the Care Supreme plan,
if your sum insured is up to ₹1 lakh, then you
can claim ₹1000000 and if the
sum insured is more than this, then there is
no capping on it, it will be actual on the covered age.
Whereas under the IG Medicare Premier
plan, if your sub insured is up to ₹1 lakh, then
you will be able to claim hospitalization up to ₹5000
and if your sum insured
is more than ₹1 lakh, then you
can cover the road ambulance expenses up to a maximum of ₹0000, but this will depend on your sum
insured, that is, how much you have
taken the policy for. When it comes to consumer bills,
That is,
how much coverage will you get for non-medical items
in all three plans? Is it
part of the standard plan or will you have to take a separate add-on?
If we talk about IIC Lord Elevate
Plan, then you will have to take a separate add-on
called Claim Protector.
After taking this add-on,
you can also cover consumable items after paying extra money.
Similarly, under the Care Plan, you will have to
take an add-on called Claim Shield, only then will
these non-medical items be covered.
But this is not the case under the AAG Medicare Premier
Plan. There, you will get
consumable items covered in the standard policy itself
and you do
not need to take any separate add-on.
You will get this coverage in the premium of the standard policy itself. Now friends, let's
talk about maternity, newborn baby cover
or vaccination cover, that is, all these are maternity-
related coverages.
What facilities will you get in these three plans? If we
talk about IIC Lord Elevate Plan, then
here you will have to take all these three features
as add-ons because the insurance
company has included standard coverage in the standard policy.  It has not been made a part of the plan. The
policyholder who needs
it can add it.
You do not get any maternity coverage under the Care Supreme Health Insurance Plan, but you can
add coverage for a newborn baby to this plan through an add-on.
What will you get here in Newborn Baby Coverage?
You can get coverage for a baby added to the policy after 91 days from day one,
but you will have to take it as an add-on.
You will get good maternity facilities under the AIG Medicare Premier Plan. If the sum in your policy is up
to ₹1 lakh, then
delivery charges up to ₹5,000,000 can be covered. If
it is a boy, that is, a boy is
born, then delivery expenses up to ₹5,000,000 can be
claimed. And
if it is a girl child, then the same expense can be
claimed up to ₹2,000,000. But if
your sum in sum is ₹75 lakh or more, then
You will be able to claim delivery expenses of ₹1 lakh for a boy child and ₹2000000 for a girl child in the
TAAG Medicare
Premier Plan. Apart from this, if there is
any complication in the delivery, then
you can claim its expenses separately in this policy
and you also get vaccination coverage
till the newborn baby turns
1 year old, so
you can cover the maximum sum insured up to ₹1 or ₹1000000 for vaccination coverage,
but the
waiting period on maternity coverage is quite high,
it is 48 months i.e. 4 years. Now
friends, let's talk about modern treatments, are
modern treatments covered in these plans, is there
any capping on them
or are some terms and
conditions applicable in them, so first of all,
modern treatments are covered up to the sum
insured in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan, there is no supplement in it
under the Care Supreme plan.  It is similar for
your modern treatments. All 12
listed modern treatments are covered up
to some in short, but in the Tata AIG
Medicare Premier Plan, there is no mention of
modern treatments in any document. There is
no mention of technologically advanced treatments, so
I do not consider them covered under this plan.
Now comes the turn of
surrogacy and oocyte donor cover, that is, if the
biological mother
conceives a baby through another biological mother and the baby
is delivered, or if the biological donor,
i.e., eggs, are donated
by another mother, then that coverage is for this type of
treatment. You
can get coverage up to ₹ lakh in the Elevate Plan.
This is
not a part of this plan in the Care Supreme Plan, neither in the standard policy
nor as an add-on, but you can take
a separate surrogacy and oocyte donor policy
in the Care Supreme Plan. It is a completely
different product design.
You will not get such coverage even in the AIG Medicare Premier Plan. Now,
friends, the matter comes  Waiting Period Reduction, an
add-on for waiting period reduction,
means you can reduce the waiting period
in any of these three policies. In the ICICI Lombard
Elevate plan,
you can reduce the waiting period for every feature, every coverage, regardless of the pre-registered coverage.
Waiting periods can also be reduced in the Care Supreme plan,
but there
is no option to reduce the waiting period in the Tata EIG Medicare Premier plan because the waiting
period is already very short, which we will
understand in the waiting period section. Now,
friends, when it comes to the total bonus, if
you purchase a policy and do not make any claims, the
company provides you with some benefit. This is also called total bonus or no
claim bonus.
In ICICI Lombard, you get a guaranteed cumulative
bonus of 20% of your sum insured. The
sum
insured will increase if you do
not make any claims for the entire year.  So
why is it called guaranteed? Because in case of any
claim, it will not decrease until you use this money. It can increase incrementally
from 20% to up to 100% of the sum
insured. This means
you can collect a curative bonus equal to your sum insured.
Under the Care Supreme plan, your curative bonus or no-claim bonus will be
50%. If you do not make a claim,
your sum insured will increase by 50% and will
increase to a maximum of 100%. This means
your sum insured will double within two years.
If a claim arises, this curative bonus will
not decrease. Whereas, under the Medicare
Premier plan, your curative
bonus is 50%. This means if you do not make a claim,
your sum insured will increase by a
maximum of 100%. However, if a
claim arises in the future,
it will also reduce by the same percentage as the 50%. Now, let
us understand the difference in very important coverage.  That is restoration
benefit or reset benefit also it can be called.
In ICICI Loard Elevate plan
you get the benefit of in-bet reset, that
is, you will be able to use your restoration benefit unlimited
times up to 100% of the sum insured.
You will not be able to use this reset benefit amount on the first claim,
but after that
you will be able to use this amount in the subsequent claims
for unlimited times.
In Care Supreme plan also you get restoration benefit up to 100% of the sum insured
for unlimited times,
but this is not the case in TAG
Medicare Premier plan. You will get restoration benefit up to
100% of the sum insured,
but you will get
this benefit only once in a year if your
policy has a sum insured of ₹ 75 lakh or more
and you have taken a policy for multiple years.
Now suppose my policy is of sum insured of ₹ 1 lakh
and I have taken a policy for 3 consecutive years
together.  If I have taken a long-term policy, I can
use this restoration benefit, which was limited to once a year, up to three times a year because
I have taken a long-term policy. If I
take a two-year policy, I will be
able to use it twice, but
in a standard policy, up to a sum of ₹1 lakh,
you will only get it once in a year. Now,
friends, comes the next benefit: compassionate
travel. If a policyholder is
away from their family members and is hospitalized there, and there is no
immediate family
member to care for them, the travel expenses of any one immediate
family member can be
covered.
You will have to avail this feature as an add-on under the IIC Lord Elevate plan.
This facility is not available under the Care Supreme plan. And
under the Tata AG Medicare Premier plan, if the
hospitalization lasts more than five days,
you can
claim an amount ranging from ₹0,000 to ₹0,000 as a compassionate visit.
This will depend on your sum in reserve.
If your policy is up to ₹1 lakh, then
you can cover travel expenses i.e. coming and going for ₹2000000 under compassionate visit.
And if your sum in reserve
is more than ₹1 lakh, then you can claim this amount up to ₹5000000
for domestic
compassionate visit. The next feature is friends,
Daily Cash for Upon a Dependent Child, that is,
if there is a dependent child in the policy
and they get admitted and their age is
less than 12 years, then you can also claim some benefit
which is ₹2000000, that is, if the
attendant will stay with them, then the
expenses of staying with the dependent child can be
claimed on a daily basis,
but you will get this facility only under the Tata AIG
Medicare Premier plan.
You will not get any such feature
in the Elevate and Care Supreme plans. The
next feature is friends, Prolong
Hospitalization Benefit, that is, any
hospitalization which  If the hospitalization lasts for a long time, then the
insurance company also
gives you a lump sum benefit in case of loss
of income, that is, your normal routine
work has been disrupted due to this admission.
So, this kind of coverage
can be availed as an add-on in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan.
You will not get such an option in Care Supreme. However,
in the Tata AAG Medicare Premier plan, this is part of the standard policy in
which you can
claim a lump sum benefit up to 1% of the sum insured if the
hospitalization lasts more than 10 days.
Now friends, the next coverage comes for OPD, that is, the
daily outpatient department
expenses. When we see a doctor, the
doctor prescribes some tests and
medicines, we pay the consultation fee,
but we are not admitted. Will such
OPD expenses be
covered in these three plans?
If you want to cover such expenses in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan, then
you will get an
add-on.  You will have to take this as an add-on. You can
avail this optional benefit in this policy. Similarly,
you can cover OPD expenses through add-on in Care Supreme as well,
but
this feature is already inbuilt in TAG Medicare Premier, but there are
some conditions here. The first condition is
that after completing the policy for 2 consecutive years,
you will get this sum insured in
which you can cover OPD expenses.
What is that amount for which
you will be able to claim expenses?
After completion of 2 years,
you can cover expenses up to ₹5000000 for normal OPD. This amount will
depend on your sum insured i.e. on your
insured amount, i.e. how much amount
you have taken the policy for. If we talk about
dental OPD, whatever root
canal treatment is there in dental OPD or whatever normal day to day
procedures are there in OPD, they can also be covered
once you have completed the 2 year
policy.  Here you will be able to deposit from ₹1000000 to
₹2500000
but this amount is 10000 to
25000 and for normal OPD it is 5000 to
10000, it will depend on how much you have taken for
Tata AIG Medicare Premier
policy. Now friends, let's talk about
accidental death coverage, that is,
if any adult policy holder dies
after an accident
during this policy tenure or any accident happens
and within 12 months of that, even if the
policy has expired, if
accidental death occurs within 12 months, then will you
get coverage under these policies? To get
this coverage under ICICI Lombard Elevate Plan,
you will have to take an add-on. There is no option of
taking such coverage under Care Supreme Plan.
Whereas in Tata AIG
Medicare Premier Plan, you will get this
feature inbuilt, whatever is the
sum insured of the policy holder, up
to that amount.  Accidental claim is
given to the family of the policy
holder in case of death. The
maximum limit of this compensation for personal
accident is ₹ lakh in Tata EIG
Medicare Premier Plan. Now friends, let's talk about
annual head checkup, that is, at the end of the year,
you can get some tests done
in your policies. Do you get coverage in these policies?
Here,
under ICICI Lombard Elevate Plan and Care
Supreme Plan, you will have to take this feature as an add-on.
After taking the add-on, you  You
can get these tests done but under the TA Easy
Medicare Premier Plan, from ₹1000000 to ₹
225000 which will depend
on your sum insured 00 to ₹2500000 if
you use any of these features, so
now friends, the
final comparison point of coverage and benefits comes, that is air
ambulance. You get the facility of air ambulance
in all these three plans, if we
talk about ICICI Lord Elevate Plan,
then here you will have to take an add-on,
in Care Supreme also you will have to take an add-on, but
under the TA Easy Medicare Premier Plan,
if the sum insured is up to ₹1 lakh, then
you get inbuilt emergency air ambulance coverage of up to ₹1 lakh and if
your sum insured is 75 lakh or more, then
it is covered up to the sum insured,
but if you use it for treatment in a panel hospital, only
then the sum
insured will be up to ₹1 lakh, otherwise this
limit will also be ₹1 lakh  It will remain till now friends, now it is the
turn to compare the add-on section, that is, the
policy which is the standard policy,
you have known the features, that is, what other
add-ons can you get in all the three plans,
first understand the add-ons of ICICI Lombard Elevate Plan, you have
seen this in previous videos as well, so
I will explain it in brief, the
first add-on is what will happen in IFA Care,
if any claim comes and
you have taken this add-on, then you
can tell the insurance company that
I do not want any limit on this claim, then
your sum insured limit will be
removed and you
can claim one claim in a lifetime up to an unlimited amount,
apart from this, there is another important add-on
friends, Jump Start, it says the
six illnesses which you can see on the
top of the screen right now,
if you want coverage for any of these diseases from the beginning, you do
not want a waiting period, then you will
get coverage from the 21st day itself,
you will not have to wait much for it  The next
add-on is Power Booster. This is the most important
add-on that ensures that your sum insured bonus will increase every
year up to 100% of the sum insured in the IIC Lord Elevate plan,
and there will be no
limit on the maximum increase.
Therefore, you can also choose the Power Booster add-on
if you want to increase your sum insured
to a significant level.
You
can also modify your room rent and modify the room rent category,
as
you get a single private AC room under the Elevate plan.
After taking the room rent modification, you can choose any room,
you can choose a twin sharing room,
and you can also apply percentage-based capping on your room
rent limit.
I already told you about maternity benefits, that
you can also cover baby delivery charges.
You can also avail newborn baby coverage, which means if
you want to get coverage from the first day of the child's birth, then
you will get that too under newborn baby coverage.
You can also avail vaccination coverage along with it. Whatever the
waiting period is, whether it is for a specific disease,
maternity or pre-
existing condition, you can reduce it.
This option is also given to you in the Elevate plan.
Apart from this, there is a BeFit rider called
BeFit which gives you coverage for OPD, whether it is
online consultation or offline consultation.
You will also get this in the Elevate plan. So,
if you finalize to take ICI Lord Elevate
plan, then to
get OPD coverage, you will have to add BeFit rider
in this policy. After this, the next add-
on comes friends, Claim Protector, in
which consumable items will be
covered in your Elevate plan. Apart from this, there is
Conversant Benefit, Compassionate Visit
and you also get coverage of durable equipment
in the Wait Plan. If you
want to take add-ons with limited benefits, then you
can take the Personal Accidental add-on,
under which Accidental Death,
Permanent Total Disability and Permanent
Partial Disability are also covered.  It will be done and
along with this, if you want to cover any serious illness, then
you can also take the add-on of critical illness in the Elevate plan.
So you have understood all these add-ons
of ICICI Lombard Elevate plan. Now let us know
what add-ons you can choose in the Care Supreme plan, through
which you will be
able to modify your policy according to your needs. So the first and
most important add-on in the Care Supreme plan is
[ __ ] Bonus Super.
If you take this add-on, then your sum insured will keep increasing up to 100%
every year and it will
increase up to a maximum of five times. Now there is
one more thing in this plan. If the age of the policy holder is
45 years or less, then this
benefit of Super No Claim Bonus is
inbuilt. You will not have to take it as an add-on.
But if the age of the policy holder is
more than 45 years or the age of the senior
member is more than 45 years, then
it is given optionally. If you
want to take it as an add-on, then you  You can take it,
otherwise you will be able to take this plan without it as well, that is,
if the age is more than 45 years, then
this is an optional cover, otherwise the
Super Complete Bonus is a permanent part of this standard policy itself.
Next add-on is
friends, the
waiting period for pre-
existing diseases is
quite high, that is 48 months, but you
can also reduce it through this add-on. The
next add-on is Shield, in this 68 non-
medical items which are consumable items will
also be covered. If you have taken the Claim Shield
add-on in your Care Supreme policy, then the
next important add-on
comes in the Care Supreme plan,
Instant Cover. If we
take the Instant Cover add-on in our policy, then we will be able to cover conditions like BP, Diabetes and
Asthma after 30 days, from the
31st day itself,
as we saw in the Jump Start add-on
which we get in the ICICI Lombard Elevate plan.
Similarly,
if you cover these three conditions like BP, Diabetes and Asthma  If
you want to be covered from the 31st day,
you will have to take this instant cover add-on in the Supreme
plan. Apart from this, if you
want to avail the facility of air ambulance, then
for that also you will get a separate add-on
in Care Supreme and annual health
checkup will also be available here as an add-on
in Care Supreme. Now, the one add-on which is
important is related to OPD.
Here in the Care Supreme plan,
you will get an add-on called Care OPD,
under which you can take offline and online
consultations. Along with this,
you will also get some physiotherapy sessions. So,
if you want to get OPD coverage, then
you will have to take the Care OPD add-on
in the Care Supreme plan. Now,
if we talk about the Medicare Premier plan,
most of the features are
part of the standard policy. You will not get any add-on here
in the Medicare Premier plan
because all the
options given by the insurance companies in these two plans are
inbuilt features in the AIG Medicare plan. So, there is no such
add-on
in the AIG Medicare Premier plan.  Not available
Now friends, before we talk about the special things of these three
plans, their
highlighted features and the shortcomings of these plans, let
us
also know the waiting period of these three plans, that is, how much
time will you have to wait for which treatment under which plan,
because if a patient has a
pre-existing disease, a policy
holder has PD or has to
take treatment for a specific disease, then the waiting period
plays a big role in the coverage of the policy, so the
first waiting period that comes is the
initial 30 days, that is, the standard
exclusion is of the first 30 days, within this 30
days you can also cancel the policy,
so within the first 30 days,
apart from accidental treatment,
you will not get any coverage in all the three plans, the
second waiting period is of specific
disease, this is a slow growing illness
which takes some time to develop, so for this
you will get a waiting period of
24 months in all the three plans, although
ICICI  In the Lombard Elevate plan,
you can also reduce this waiting period.
Now comes the turn of Pre-
Existing.
In the Lombard Elevate plan, it is 36 months
i.e. 3 years. From 3 years, you can reduce it to 2 years or
even 1 year by
paying an extra premium. On the other hand, in the Care Supreme
plan, the waiting period for PET is
very high; it is 48 months i.e. 4 years.
However, you can also reduce this time through a PD reduction add-on.
And the most important and important thing is the
PD
waiting period. In the Tata AAG Medicare
Premier plan, you will
get only the standard PD waiting period of
24 months i.e. only 2 years. Any
pre-existing disease will be
covered under this plan only after 2 years. The only
condition is that you
must have declared your pre-existing disease at the time of taking the policy.
However, there is also maternity coverage
in the Tata AAG Medicare Premier plan, so
its waiting period is also 48 months.
Now friends, it's time to discuss the
highlighted features of these plans, which are important
features, and what are their shortcomings.
First,
we've done some videos on the ISA Lord Elevate plan,
so you already
know about its highlighted features, which are important features. The most
important features of these are
also shown in the theme of this plan. That is, the
add-on called IFNA Benefits, that is, IFNA Care,
IFNA Sum Insured, IFNA Reset, IFNA
Conazole,
that is, its flexible
standard plan. If you
get all the features, then it is possible that not every
policyholder may need all those features. So,
picking and choosing,
modifying your policy as an add-on, personalizing it,
is a much better option than
giving the benefits of a fixed policy.
Now, along with this, you
also get maternity coverage as a do-in.
Apart from this, the Jump Start add-on is
also quite unique, in which you can get 31
You can cover the six listed illnesses from the 10th day onwards. So, no
shortcomings have been left in the plan.
Every
effort has been made to provide all kinds of features in it. But the
biggest drawback of this plan that I have noticed is
that if some clients
go for porting the policy, then they will have to
take some essential add-ons along with it, that is, the
insurance company now also imposes compulsion with these add-ons. So, this
flexible
option of choosing add-ons is
only for fresh policy holders.
If you port the policy, then
according to the previous coverage of your policy,
you will have to take some add-ons.
You will not have the option to remove them. So,
here the
benefit of the flexible one seems to be reduced a bit.
But an Essential Pack has been created for fresh policy holders, in
which you
can take these add-ons without thinking. There are
five-six essential add-ons.
If you take that entire pack, then you will get good coverage in your policy.
And there is
no add-on in the basic pack. You can take
your  You can pick and choose as per your wish. There
is no compulsion for anyone here,
but if you port the policy, then you will have to
face this compulsion condition. Now let's
talk about the special features of Supreme Plan.
First, there is
no limit on the entry age. The limit is 99 years, which
means that people of much higher age group will
also be able to take this policy for the first time. The
second important feature is Cumulative Bonus Super, which means that
you can increase your sum in amount up to five times
if you take this add-on.
But if your age is less than 45 years, then
you will get this as part of the standard policy. This will
increase your sum in amount up to seven times because there is a basic sum in
amount, apart from that there is your normal cumulative
bonus, then super cumulative bonus, then cumulative
bonus super. In this way, you
can also increase your sum in amount up to seven times. The
third important feature in it,
which is very important, is instant cover, which
means that if a policy holder
needs very quick coverage from any of his pre-
aging diseases.  Related features like BP or
diabetes
can be covered by taking an instant cover. Now,
I feel that many of the features here are
neither provided in the standard policy
nor in advance.
However, at the time when this plan was launched, there were
not so many innovative plans,
meaning there were not so many features in the plans.
But if we talk about today's comparison, then it has
many features like
maternity features or many
small benefits which I find
missing, which
we do not get in this plan. Now comes the turn of
Medicare Premier Plan. This is a
very popular plan of T&E. In this, you get
maternity facility and OPD facility
inbuilt. Apart from this, there are small
road ambulances, air ambulance,
conversion benefit, compassionate visit,
annual health checkup. Many of the features
which you will see as add-ons in the Elevate plan,
you will
get them as part of the standard policy in this plan, which
means if someone without thinking  Understand that
if you want to buy a policy, then if you buy this policy, then
you can cover most of the things
without much thinking or without much
research. Now, your
consumer cover is also inbuilt in this plan, which
means you will not have to take any additional loan. And
look at the waiting period of PD, it is so short, there is a waiting
period of only 24 months. If
someone has a pre-existing disease, then you
can cover that pre-existing disease after 24 months with this standard plan, provided
you declare it when you
take the policy. Now, there are
some shortcomings of TAAG Medicare Premier, let us also
know about them once. The first shortcoming that I feel is
that there is no mention of modern treatments anywhere.
Although I am saying this only on the basis of
document-based research, that is, there is
no mention of modern treatments anywhere in their policy statement, then it is possible that it may not be covered.
And if the coverage is not mentioned in the document, then
I will
understand that that thing is not covered. But if
they cover modern treatments,  If we do this,
this shortcoming will not remain. But at present, I did not see any
coverage of evidence-based modern treatments anywhere in this
plan. The
second shortcoming that I feel in this is that the
cumulate bonus is not enough. If we
compare it with the Elevate plan, then there
you can increase your cumulates by taking add-ons for unlimited times,
but here you will only get
50% of the sum insured and
you will get cumulate bonus only up to a maximum of 100 times
as an option, like in the
Care Supreme plan, you get cumulate
bonus super. No such
option has been given separately, where you
can increase the sum insured to a good amount without paying extra premium. The
next shortcoming that I found in the TA AG Medicare
Premier plan is the
maximum entry age of its adult members, i.e., the
maximum entry age capping is
kept only up to 65 years. However, in the other
two plans where we are comparing, the
maximum entry age for adults is 125 years, 25 years and 99 years.  If the age
is higher, then members in the higher age group will
not be able to avail this plan. Apart from this, two
more drawbacks that I feel are that if
these features were provided as advance instead of standard features, then it is
possible that
if a policy holder does not need
these features of these plans, then they could have
saved their premium, thus providing
some flexibility in this plan.
However, the special thing about this plan is
that you are getting good coverage as a package,
but if you are the kind of
policy holder who wants to customize your plan as per your convenience, then
this plan does
not provide you that facility. The last
disadvantage that I feel
in the Easy Medicare Premier plan is the
waiting period for maternity coverage. Now, brother,
you have provided coverage of delivery charges of Rs 50,000, Rs 60,000, Rs 1 lakh,
but there is a
waiting period of 48 months, that is a
waiting period of 4 years, which cannot be reduced
by any add-on, so this is quite
long. Now friends, we have reached the end.  At the
last stage of this comparison,
we will now compare the prices of these three policies, that is, the
features and
benefits that you will get. If you have finalized any of these
plans, then how much will
this plan cost you? For this, the
standard family size we have taken is
two adults and two children. The age of the adults is
38 and 35 years and the age of the children is 12 and
9 years. Here we are taking coverage of ₹1 lakh,
but the
coverage taken under AIG Medicare Premier is 10 lakh.
If we talk about the IIC Lombard Elevate
plan, then two add-ons
are included in it, that is room rent modification, so
we have made that limit on any room
because there is no limit on room rent in the other two plans. Along with
this,
we have also given the add-on of Power Booster, in
which
you can collect curative bonus up to an unlimited amount. So for this, this
family will have to pay for the entire year.
₹
1,265 only. And if we talk about the Care Supreme
plan, then here you will
get five add-ons along with the standard policy.
Which add-ons are Comat Bonus, Super
Air Ambulance, Wellness Benefits, Health
Checkup and along with this, Claim Shield
add-on, you will get these five add-ons compulsory in this age group. The
coverage is of ₹1 lakh,
for this you will have to pay ₹2,377 for the entire year.
Whereas if we talk about
how much the same family will have to pay to take the Tata EIG Medicare Premier plan, then here the coverage
is of ₹10 lakh, I have checked the premium
and its annual premium will be ₹
3,178 only. Now you have seen that with these features and
these coverages,
you will get these plans at this price. Now you
also know the affordability of these plans, which
plan is more expensive to take. So
friends, you saw this comparison of ICICI
Lord Elevate plan, Care Supreme plan
and Tata EIG.  If we compare Medicare Premier Plans with
each other, then
what is the bottom line, you will
understand that by the end of this video. By the way, I have
also given you my verdict and my opinion
in this video. Along with this,
we have also compared the prices. If
you have any opinion on any point or you have
any doubt or you have any query and
you want to know about it, then
please comment in the comment section. You can
also use the comment section to tell which part of the video you liked.
If you understood the video and if this
video has
created even a little value for you, then to show your love and support, do
not forget to like the video and share it where necessary. If
you have been associated with this channel for some time
and you follow the videos of this channel
and you feel that the content coming here is
valuable for you and
helps you in some way, then
please subscribe to the channel so that we can also know
that we are getting your support.
I am Harvinder Singh. Now I take your permission. I will meet
you in the next video. Till then  Take
care of yourself, stay happy and healthy,
Jai Hind